<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcements | Learning iPad Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/category/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-20T11:11:29-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons Available for Purchase]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/13/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons-available-for-purchase/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/13/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons-available-for-purchase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learned today that the <a href='http://www.informit.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=0321821661'>Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons</a> videos are available for purchase from the <a href='http://www.informit.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=0321821661'>InformIT web site</a>. So you don&#8217;t need a Safari Books Online account to purchase and enjoy these training videos.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/12/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/12/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href='http://bit.ly/ipadlivelessons'><img src='http://my.safaribooksonline.com/images/9780132981163/9780132981163_s.jpg' vspace='10' width='145' border='0' align='left' hspace='10' height='174' /></a>
<p>I should mention not all topics found in the book are covered in the LiveLessons. There simply wasn&#8217;t enough time to cover everything. Besides, covering everything may have resulted in 20 hours of videos instead of the 8 and half hours available today. Still, if you are new to iPad programming, and you are looking for an alternative way to learn iPad programming then check out <a href='http://bit.ly/ipadlivelessons'>Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons</a>.</p>

<p>Attention iPad users with a Safari Books Online account: You can watch the Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons from your iPad using the <a href='http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/click?id=joxFicmfXq8&amp;subid=&amp;offerid=146261.1&amp;type=10&amp;tmpid=3909&amp;RD_PARM1=http%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fapp%2Fsafari-to-go%2Fid385824712%3Fmt%3D8'>Safari To Go</a> iPad app.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Versions Are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took the publisher longer than expected, but I&#8217;m happy to finally report Learning iPad Programming is once again available for <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle</a> and iBooks. And the formatting issues have been corrected.</p>

<p>For those who purchased the Kindle or iBooks version back before they were pulled…I purchased the Kindle and iBooks versions when they were first released at the beginning of December. I was able to update my iBooks version the other day by deleting the book from my device and re-downloading it. Updating the Kindle version is more involved. It requires Amazon to send you an email asking if you wish to update. Amazon does this because installing an update will overwrite your highlights and bookmarks for the book being updated. So far, I have not received my email from Amazon informing me of the update and giving me the option to update. I hope it comes soon because I want to see the latest and greatest on my Kindle.</p>

<p>Update: I found that emailing Amazon at <a href='mailto:kindle-feedback@amazon.com'>kindle-feedback@amazon.com</a> and requesting the latest version is the quickest way to get the updated Kindle version pushed out to your device.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manuscript is complete!!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/09/manuscript-is-complete/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/09/manuscript-is-complete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I made a <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kirbyt/status/112092725574242304'>tweet</a> that I&#8217;ve being waiting to do for a verify long time.</p>
<a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kirbyt/status/112092725574242304'><img src='http://ipadprogbook.wpsblogs.com/files/2011/09/tweet-manuscriptcomplete.png' width='600' border='0' alt='Tweet manuscriptcomplete' height='196' /></a>
<p>Yep, the manuscript is complete. A part of me thought this day would never come. But it&#8217;s here and I couldn&#8217;t be happier. Tom and I will be doing some edits over the next few weeks then the book heads off to the printers.</p>

<p>With the writing part finally out of the way, I can turn my attention to this web site. I have a number of how to blog posts queued up that will expand on the book. Stay tune. The best is yet to come.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Tom Harrington]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/03/welcome-tom-harrington/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/03/welcome-tom-harrington</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working so hard on completing the book that I forgot to officially welcome Tom Harrington as co-author of Learning iPad Programming.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve known Tom for a couple of years now. Our paths have crossed multiple times at conferences and on client projects. At WWDC this year, I accepted the reality that I cannot complete the book this summer without some help. Tom quickly came to mind as someone perfect to co-author the book with me. I already had a sense of what it&#8217;s like working with Tom, but even better than that, Tom is already a published author. He has co-authored two other iOS related books: <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430224037/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=1430224037'>iPhone Advanced Projects</a><img src='http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=1430224037&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369' width='1' style='border:none !important;margin:0px !important' border='0' alt='' height='1' /> and most recently <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321670426/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&amp;creativeASIN=0321670426'>Core Data for iOS: Developing Data-Driven Applications for the iPad, iPhone, and iPod touch</a><img src='http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0321670426&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369' width='1' style='border:none !important;margin:0px !important' border='0' alt='' height='1' />.</p>

<p>Words can&#8217;t express my gratitude towards Tom for stepping up and helping me complete the book. Tom and I have already been working together on the book for the last couple of months, and the manuscript is nearly complete.</p>

<p>Thanks Tom, and welcome aboard!</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>