<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-28T08:49:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright (c) 2011-2013 White Peak Software Inc</rights>
  
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Harrington is Blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/05/28/tom-harrington-is-blogging/"/>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/05/28/tom-harrington-is-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve done a horrible job of blogging here, but worry not. Tom Harrington has been actively blogging over at the <a href='http://www.atomicbird.com'>Atomic Bird House</a>. Be sure to checkout Tom&#8217;s series on <a href='http://www.atomicbird.com/category:iCloud'>iCloud</a> where he talks about the ugly truth of Core Data syncing using iCloud.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition, is Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-2nd-edition-is-available/"/>
    <published>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/05/28/learning-ipad-programming-2nd-edition-is-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m excited to announce the second edition of <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20'>Learning iPad Programming</a> is now on sale at your favorite book store. The second edition has been updated to cover features found in iOS 6.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhotoWheel 2 is Available for Download]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/30/photowheel-2-available-for-download/"/>
    <published>2013-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/30/photowheel-2-available-for-download</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest version of PhotoWheel, version 2, has been approved by Apple and is being processed for the App Store. This means you will be able to download the latest and greatest within the next 24-hours.</p>

<p>PhotoWheel 2 has been updated with the latest code from the second edition of Learning iPad Programming, which is scheduled for release sometime in May 2013. I decided to release PhotoWheel 2 now instead of waiting until May because I thought other developers could benefit from the enhancements made to the code base.</p>

<p>PhotoWheel has been re-written for iOS 6. It takes advantage of new features found in iOS 6 such as the activity view controller and collection views. Collection views, one of my favorite additions to iOS, are an welcome addition because it eliminates the need for writing a custom grid view, which was the approach used in the first edition of the book.</p>

<p>Source code for the App Store version of PhotoWheel is available in the <a href='https://github.com/kirbyt/PhotoWheel'>github repository</a>. Also, the older, iOS 5 version of PhotoWheel has been tagged in the repository as <a href='https://github.com/kirbyt/PhotoWheel/tree/v1.3'>v1.3</a>.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition Coming in Spring 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/23/2edition-coming-spring-2013/"/>
    <published>2013-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/23/2edition-coming-spring-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition is coming this spring. Tom and I updated the book to cover new features found in iOS 6 including collection views, <code>UIActivityViewController</code>, unwind segues, simpler iCloud syncing setup, and Cocoa Auto Layout. There&#8217;s also a new chapter on turning your iPad app into a universal app. <a href='http://my.safaribooksonline.com/9780133138702'>Rough Cuts</a> are available at Safari Books Online for those looking to get an early preview of the book.</p>

<p>Also, look for an update to <a href='http://www.photowheelapp.com/'>PhotoWheel</a> coming soon in the App Store. PhotoWheel has been updated to take advantage of new features found in iOS 6. And as with the first edition, the entire source code for the App Store version of PhotoWheel is available in the <a href='https://github.com/kirbyt/PhotoWheel'>github repository</a>.</p>

<p>You maybe asking yourself, &#8220;Should I buy the first edition or wait for the second edition?&#8221; If you are writing an iPad app today that must target iOS 5, then the first edition is the book for you. New features in iOS 6 such as collection views and the activity view controller are not available in iOS 5. However, if you plan to support iOS 6 and newer, then I suggest waiting until the second edition is available for purchase. Or if you like, <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20'>pre-order Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition</a> from Amazon now.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Class Declaration versus Class Definition]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/07/26/class-declaration-versus-class-definition/"/>
    <published>2012-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/07/26/class-declaration-versus-class-definition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A reader sent me an outstanding question. He pointed out that in chapter 4 of Learning iPad Programming, I wrote:</p>

<p>&#8220;To define a class you use <code>@interface</code>. In Listing 4.2, the <code>CoinTosser</code> class definition starts with the line <code>@interface CoinTosser : NSObject</code>. <code>@interface</code> is Objective-C syntax that tells the compiler that what follows is a class definition. <code>CoinTosser</code> is the name of the class. The colon character separates the class name from the name of the superclass. The new class inherits properties and methods from the superclass. The class definition starts with @interface and ends at the first occurrence of @end. This tells the compiler it has reached the end of the class definition.&#8221;</p>

<p>The reader asked, &#8220;Shouldn&#8217;t class definition be class declaration?&#8221; It turns out, class definition is correct.</p>

<p>While many programmers might use declaration and definition interchangeability, there are subtle differences in C and C++. And since Objective-C is a superset of C, those subtle differences apply.</p>

<p>A class <strong>declaration</strong> tells the compiler that a class exists. A class <strong>definition</strong> tells the compiler all the needed information to create an instance of the class. It tells the compiler about its member functions, properties, and so on. With Objective-C, the difference between class declaration and definition can be seen in the syntax.</p>

<p><code>@class className</code> declares a class, so it&#8217;s a class declaration. It tells the compiler the name of a class. This is also known as a &#8220;forward declaration.&#8221;</p>

<p><code>@interface className</code> and its contents defines the class, so it&#8217;s a class definition. It tells the compiler all it needs to know about the class, how to create an instance, what properties and methods are contained in the class, and so on.</p>

<p>Here are a couple of additional links that explain the differences as seen in C and C++:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href='http://www.daniweb.com/software-development/cpp/threads/143198/difference-between-a-class-declaration-and-a-class-definition'>Difference between a class declaration and a class definition</a></li>

<li><a href='http://www.cprogramming.com/declare_vs_define.html'>Declare vs Define in C and C++</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Xcode Code Snippets]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/19/using-xcode-code-snippets/"/>
    <published>2012-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/19/using-xcode-code-snippets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you tried Xcode code snippets? If not, head over to InformIT.com to read an article I wrote on being more <a href='http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1914191'>productive using Xcode code snippets</a>.</p>

<p>Speaking of Xcode code snippets, Cocoaholic has released a Mac app called <a href='http://cocoaholic.com/snippet_edit/'>Snippet Edit</a> that makes it possible to edit your code snippets as well as the standard ones without using Xcode. I haven&#8217;t tried the app yet, but it does look interesting.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Appsterdam Visit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/06/my-appsterdam-visit/"/>
    <published>2012-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/06/my-appsterdam-visit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple of weeks ago I had the pleasure of visiting Amsterdam with my family. Amsterdam is a beautiful city with great restaurants and super friendly people. Getting around Amsterdam is really easy. We walked most of the time, but found the trains to be convenient when we wanted to return to the hotel quickly.</p>
<img border='0' width='125' style='float:left' height='96' alt='Appsterdam logo smaller' src='/images/blog/2012-06-06/appsterdam-logo-smaller.png' />
<p><a href='http://mur.mu.rs/?p=196'>What is Appsterdam</a>? Appsterdam is a growing movement, and organization, bringing together app makers from around the world. It&#8217;s anchored in Amsterdam, a city with a diverse population of some of the friendliest people in the world. <a href='http://www.meetup.com/Appsterdam/'>Appsterdam hosts various meet-ups</a>, from weekly luncheon lectures and to monthly family fun weekend. And they even provide a co-working space available to those living in Amsterdam as well as for those just visiting.</p>

<p>As luck would have it, I had an opportunity to speak at one of the Appsterdam luncheons, and I attended a social gathering later that evening. This gave me a chance to meeting many of the local Appsterdamers, which to my surprise are from all over the world. In fact, I met a number of Americans who now call Amsterdam home. Meeting this international group of app makers proved to me that Amsterdam is not only a great place to live, it&#8217;s a great place to run an indie software company. And if it wasn&#8217;t for my love and desire to live in a ski town, I might try to convenience my wife we need to move there. While moving there is not an option for us, extended stays most certainly are, and I hope to make it happen (hint, hint to my wife).</p>

<p>While traveling abroad is not easy for everyone - the airfare alone can be costly - there is a way to get a taste of Appsterdam right here in the States. In San Francisco during next week&#8217;s WWDC, Appsterdam will be hosting the <a href='http://www.robelkin.com/wwdc/'>Appsterdam WWDC HQ</a>, a free, week long co-working space (June 11 through 15) and daily talks from <a href='http://www.robelkin.com/wwdc/speakers.html'>outstanding speakers</a>. Appsterdam WWDC HQ is open to all. A WWDC badge is not required.</p>

<p>If you are in SF during WWDC, with or without a badge, I encourage you to stop by <a href='http://www.robelkin.com/wwdc/'>Appterdam WWDC HQ</a> and get a taste for what this organization and movement has to offer app markers.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Ignore performSelector Leak Warning]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/04/03/how-to-ignore-performselector-leak-warning/"/>
    <published>2012-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/04/03/how-to-ignore-performselector-leak-warning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Listing 16.22 from the Learning iPad Programming book, I show how to invoke a method using <code>-performSelector:</code> where the selector is determined at runtime from a set of names stored in an NSArray. The implementation in Listing 16.22 could have been done a number of different ways, but I chose this approach to show how to set and perform a selector at runtime. However, the code produces a compiler warning message when ARC is used.</p>

<p>Because ARC is used and the selector is determined at run, the compiler generates a &#8220;possible memory leak&#8221; warning message. This warning is legitimate given that the selector is unknown at compile time and ARC is being used to manage memory.</p>

<p>At the time the code in Listing 16.22 was written, there was no way to ignore this warning message. That can be a good thing since explicitly ignoring a warning message from the compiler can be a bad thing. 99.9% of the time you want to fix or refactor your code so the warning message goes away. However, there are times when you know more than the compiler does, and the code in Listing 16.22 is one of those rare times.</p>

<p>In this particular case, each selector that can potentially be called will not cause a memory leak because each one returns a void. The compiler doesn&#8217;t know this, but you (as the programmer) know this to be true. So this warning message can safely be ignored. But how do you tell the compiler to ignore the <code>-performSelector:</code> possible memory leak warning so you don&#8217;t have to see the warning message each time you compile the project?</p>

<p>You can use tell clang to ignore the -performSelector leak warning by wrapping the <code>-performSelector:</code> call with a set of <code>#pragma</code> statements that temporarily ignore the warning for the code included in the block. Here is an example:</p>
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><div class='code'> <div class='highlight'><table><tr><td class='gutter'><pre class='line-numbers'><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='objc'><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic push</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic ignored &quot;-Warc-performSelector-leaks&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>self</span> <span class='nl'>performSelector:</span><span class='n'>selector</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic pop</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></div></notextile></div>
<p>So the code causing the warning message in Listing 16.22 for the PhotoWheel app now looks like this:</p>
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><div class='code'> <div class='highlight'><table><tr><td class='gutter'><pre class='line-numbers'><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='objc'><span class='line'><span class='k'>-</span> <span class='p'>(</span><span class='kt'>void</span><span class='p'>)</span><span class='nf'>actionSheet:</span><span class='p'>(</span><span class='n'>UIActionSheet</span> <span class='o'>*</span><span class='p'>)</span><span class='nv'>actionSheet</span> <span class='nf'>clickedButtonAtIndex:</span><span class='p'>(</span><span class='n'>NSInteger</span><span class='p'>)</span><span class='nv'>buttonIndex</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='p'>{</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='c1'>// Do nothing if the user taps outside the action </span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='c1'>// sheet (thus closing the popover containing the</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='c1'>// action sheet).</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='k'>if</span> <span class='p'>(</span><span class='n'>buttonIndex</span> <span class='o'>&lt;</span> <span class='mi'>0</span><span class='p'>)</span> <span class='p'>{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class='k'>return</span><span class='p'>;</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='p'>}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='n'>NSMutableArray</span> <span class='o'>*</span><span class='n'>names</span> <span class='o'>=</span> <span class='p'>[[</span><span class='n'>NSMutableArray</span> <span class='n'>alloc</span><span class='p'>]</span> <span class='n'>init</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='k'>if</span> <span class='p'>([</span><span class='n'>actionSheet</span> <span class='n'>tag</span><span class='p'>]</span> <span class='o'>==</span> <span class='mi'>0</span><span class='p'>)</span> <span class='p'>{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>names</span> <span class='nl'>addObject:</span><span class='s'>@&quot;confirmDeletePhotoAlbum&quot;</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='p'>}</span> <span class='k'>else</span> <span class='p'>{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class='kt'>BOOL</span> <span class='n'>hasCamera</span> <span class='o'>=</span> <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>UIImagePickerController</span> <span class='nl'>isSourceTypeAvailable:</span><span class='n'>UIImagePickerControllerSourceTypeCamera</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class='k'>if</span> <span class='p'>(</span><span class='n'>hasCamera</span><span class='p'>)</span> <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>names</span> <span class='nl'>addObject:</span><span class='s'>@&quot;presentCamera&quot;</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>names</span> <span class='nl'>addObject:</span><span class='s'>@&quot;presentPhotoLibrary&quot;</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='p'>}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='kt'>SEL</span> <span class='n'>selector</span> <span class='o'>=</span> <span class='n'>NSSelectorFromString</span><span class='p'>([</span><span class='n'>names</span> <span class='nl'>objectAtIndex:</span><span class='n'>buttonIndex</span><span class='p'>]);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic push</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic ignored &quot;-Warc-performSelector-leaks&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>   <span class='p'>[</span><span class='n'>self</span> <span class='nl'>performSelector:</span><span class='n'>selector</span><span class='p'>];</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='cp'>#pragma clang diagnostic pop</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class='p'>}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></div></notextile></div>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/using-xcode-4-2-on-snow-leopard/"/>
    <published>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/using-xcode-4-2-on-snow-leopard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few people have recently mentioned to me that they are still running Snow Leopard (Mac OS X 10.6). The latest version of Xcode requires Lion (Mac OS X 10.7), however, Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard is still available for download from the Apple web site.</p>

<p>Learning iPad Programming was written based on Xcode 4.2, so everything covered in the book, with one exception, works with Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard. The one exception is the &#8220;Allows External Storage&#8221; flag in Core Data. This flag is discussed in Chapter 13 on Page 308, and the flag requires Lion. Compile errors are generated if you set this flag while running on Snow Leopard. Not to worry. You can still build the app without setting this flag. The app, after all, is a sample app so for the purpose of learning it is okay to not use this flag when using Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard.</p>

<p>To download Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard, go to <a href='https://developer.apple.com/downloads/'>https://developer.apple.com/downloads/</a> and sign in with your Apple Developer ID. In the search box, type &#8220;Xcode 4.2&#8221;. The search results will show Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard (see the screenshot below). Use this version of Xcode if you are still running on Snow Leopard.</p>

<p><img alt='Downloads' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/Downloads.png' /></p>

<p>As an alternative, you can sign into the <a href='https://developer.apple.com/devcenter/ios/'>iOS Dev Center</a> and scroll down to the Downloads area to find the download link to Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard.</p>

<p><img alt='iOS Dev Center Apple Developer' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/iOS-Dev-Center-Apple-Developer.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is There an Issue with the Print Version]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/is-there-an-issue-with-the-print-version/"/>
    <published>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/is-there-an-issue-with-the-print-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning iPad Programming has received two negative reviews on Amazon, both concerning the print quality of the book. I&#8217;ve received a number of inquires because of these two reviews, so I decided to make a blog posting.</p>

<p><strong>In short, there is nothing wrong with the print quality of the book.</strong> The paper stock is a little thin, but beyond that, the print version is of the same high quality as other programming books from Addison Wesley. This of course is my opinion, and my opinion is based on reading the book myself and comparing it to the many other programming book I own.</p>

<p>That said, I would like to address the concerns mentioned in the two reviews, which are available <a href='http://www.amazon.com/review/R19TKCFJHSKQUW/ref=cm_cr_pr_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=0321750403&amp;amp;nodeID=&amp;amp;tag=&amp;amp;linkCode='>here</a> and <a href='http://www.amazon.com/review/R2XCRENVK65S89/ref=cm_cr_pr_perm?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=0321750403&amp;amp;nodeID=&amp;amp;tag=&amp;amp;linkCode='>here</a>.</p>

<h2 id='responding_to_the_reviews'>Responding to the Reviews</h2>

<p>The first review says, &#8220;This print version uses very small fonts, the figures are poor black/grey/white renderings of color images, and the paper is thin enough that the other side of the page is faintly visible.&#8221; Let me address each point.</p>

<p>&#8220;Very small fonts.&#8221; I disagree with this. The font size is the same size found in many other programming books including those from Addison Wesley.</p>

<p>&#8220;The figures are poor black/grey/white renderings of color images.&#8221; It is true that figure images are greyscale version of color images. The images are screenshots taken from my MacBook Pro and iPad, which means the images were originally color. But the greyscale rendering of the images is on par with other print books that I have compared. I guess it could be a matter of personal preference, but I have no issue with the quality of the greyscale images. That said, I wish the figure images were printed in full color, but that would only raise the cost of the book without providing additional value.</p>

<p>&#8220;The paper is thin enough that the other side of the page is faintly visible.&#8221; This is true, and it&#8217;s my one and only complaint about the print book. The paper stock is a little thin. The issue has been brought to the publisher&#8217;s attention, and they plan to use a thicker paper stock in the future. When that will happen is something I don&#8217;t know, but I have been told future printings will use thicker paper stock. (As of this writing, there have been two printings of the book, both using the thinner paper stock.)</p>

<p>As for being able to see print from the other side, yes, this is true, but it is faint and I only notice it in white space areas. It does not district me from reading the book, but <a href='http://netforbeginners.about.com/od/xyz/f/What-Is-YMMV.htm'>YMMV</a>. I&#8217;ll also point out that a number of other print books do the same. For example, while comparing my book to <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321535022/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321535022'>Cocoa Design Patterns</a>, I noticed print from the other side is slightly visible and it uses a slightly thicker paper stock. In my opinion, this is something that happens when black ink is printed on most white paper stock. I even notice this on printouts from my home printer using standard quality inkjet paper stock.</p>

<p>The second review has this to say, &#8220;I became more and more frustrated with trying to read the small type printed in ink so light that it looked as if the printing press had run out of ink. The code listing font is even more difficult to read.&#8221;</p>

<p>Again, the font size is the same size found in many other books from Addison Wesley, and the code listings use the some font size. The only difference is the font style. A monospace font is used for the source code listing.</p>

<p>The light ink that &#8220;looked as if the printing press has run out of ink&#8221;, well, all I can say is it is possible that the reviewer did receive a defective book. However, I have reviewed 35 print versions from the first printing, and I did not find a single book with the issue of light ink. Again, it&#8217;s possible the individual received a defective book, but defective books are not common.</p>

<p>So is there a problem with the print version of Learning iPad Programming? Absolutely not. The paper stock is thin, and I wish that was not the case, but it does not, in my opinion, take away from the readability of the book. As for the font size, quality of figure images, etc, well, that&#8217;s probably a matter of preference.</p>

<h2 id='how_to_decide'>How to Decide</h2>

<p>How can you decide if the print quality is suitable for you? Here are some options for you:</p>

<p>1) Visit a brick and mortar book store and flip through the pages yourself. I know this is not an option for everyone especially those living outside the U.S., but for those living nearing a Barnes and Noble, stop by the store and compare the print quality to that of other programming books. I&#8217;m sure you will see little to no difference.</p>

<p>2) Take a look at this <a href='http://ptgmedia.pearsoncmg.com/images/9780321750402/samplepages/0321750403.pdf'>sample PDF</a>. While not exactly the same as having a printed copy of the book in your hands, you can see what fonts are used, font sizes, the quality of the figure images, and so on. It is the best representation of the print book without holding the actual book in your hands.</p>

<p>3) Take a look at the photos posted below. These are photographs of random pages from the book. I&#8217;m no photographer, so the pictures could be a little better - a lot better in fact - but as you can see the font size and print quality are very readable.</p>

<p>4) Buy the ebook edition. The book is available in the <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle Book Store</a>, iBooks Store, and from <a href='http://www.informit.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=0321750403'>informIT.com</a> as PDF and epub. This option also saves trees, and it has become my prefer way to purchase new books.</p>

<p>Compare the <a href='http://ptgmedia.pearsoncmg.com/images/9780321750402/samplepages/0321750403.pdf'>sample PDF</a> and photos below then decide for yourself if the print version is suitable for you. And if by chance you happen to receive a deflective book then let me know. Send me specific page numbers, and I can request a warehouse inspection. Or send me the book, and I&#8217;ll make sure you receive a good copy.</p>

<h2 id='all_feedback_is_good_feedback'>All Feedback is Good Feedback</h2>

<p>One last point to make. In no way am I saying the two individuals should not have posted the reviews. On the contrary, all feedback, good and bad, is welcome. All feedback is good feedback in my opinion. And if these individuals had not posted the reviews then the publisher would not have agreed to use a thicker paper stock in the future. So post your review, good or bad, to Amazon. It will help make this book and others that much better.</p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3920.jpg' /></p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3924.jpg' /></p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3926.jpg' /></p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3928.jpg' /></p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3929.jpg' /></p>

<p><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/IMG_3933.jpg' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons Available for Purchase]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/13/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons-available-for-purchase/"/>
    <published>2012-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-03-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/13/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons-available-for-purchase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learned today that the <a href='http://www.informit.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=0321821661'>Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons</a> videos are available for purchase from the <a href='http://www.informit.com/'>InformIT web site</a>. So you don&#8217;t need a Safari Books Online account to purchase and enjoy these training videos.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/12/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons/"/>
    <published>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/12/learning-ipad-programming-livelessons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img border='0' width='145' align='left' height='174' vspace='10' hspace='10' src='/images/blog/2012-03-12/9780132981163_s.jpg' />
<p>I should mention not all topics found in the book are covered in the LiveLessons. There simply wasn&#8217;t enough time to cover everything. Besides, covering everything may have resulted in 20 hours of videos instead of the 8 and half hours available today. Still, if you are new to iPad programming, and you are looking for an alternative way to learn iPad programming then check out <a href='http://bit.ly/ipadlivelessons'>Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons</a>.</p>

<p>Attention iPad users with a Safari Books Online account: You can watch the Learning iPad Programming LiveLessons from your iPad using the <a href='http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/click?id=joxFicmfXq8&amp;amp;subid=&amp;amp;offerid=146261.1&amp;amp;type=10&amp;amp;tmpid=3909&amp;amp;RD_PARM1=http%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fapp%2Fsafari-to-go%2Fid385824712%3Fmt%3D8'>Safari To Go</a> iPad app.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Versions Are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2/"/>
    <published>2012-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took the publisher longer than expected, but I&#8217;m happy to finally report Learning iPad Programming is once again available for <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle</a> and iBooks. And the formatting issues have been corrected.</p>

<p>For those who purchased the Kindle or iBooks version back before they were pulled…I purchased the Kindle and iBooks versions when they were first released at the beginning of December. I was able to update my iBooks version the other day by deleting the book from my device and re-downloading it. Updating the Kindle version is more involved. It requires Amazon to send you an email asking if you wish to update. Amazon does this because installing an update will overwrite your highlights and bookmarks for the book being updated. So far, I have not received my email from Amazon informing me of the update and giving me the option to update. I hope it comes soon because I want to see the latest and greatest on my Kindle.</p>

<p>Update: I found that emailing Amazon at <a href='mailto:kindle-feedback@amazon.com'>kindle-feedback@amazon.com</a> and requesting the latest version is the quickest way to get the updated Kindle version pushed out to your device.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Stores versions will be available soon]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon/"/>
    <published>2011-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Kindle and iBooks versions of the book have been pulled from the stores while the publisher fixes the content format issues. Once the issues have been fixed, the books will once again be available for purchase.</p>

<p>Also, I&#8217;ve been told that those who have already purchased the ebook will have the option to upgrade to the corrected version.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m very sorry for any inconvenience this may have caused.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Versions are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available/"/>
    <published>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle</a> and iBooks Store versions of Learning iPad Programming are now available for purchase and download. This is exciting but at the same time a little disappointing for me. Why? I&#8217;m not happy with some of the formatting errors found in the digital version of the book. The two most obvious formatting errors are shortcut keys and source code listings.</p>

<p>Something strange happened with the shortcut keys. Tom and I were asked to use the Command symbol (⌘) instead of typing the word Command. For example, Option-⌘-4 instead of Command-Option-4 (which was my style before writing this book). Two things happened with the Command symbol. First, in cases were it is displayed in the epub version of the book, the symbol floats up high. In the Kindle version, the symbol appears on its own line. But worse than this is when the letter &#8220;c&#8221; is displayed in place of the Command symbol.</p>

<p>Chapter 2 is the worse hit chapter with regard to the &#8220;c&#8221; problem, as I know call it. So instead of seeing Option-⌘-4 you see Option-c-4. These two keystroke sequences are completely different, and trust me, Tom and I did not type in Option-c-4 in the manuscript. We used the Command symbol, but unfortunately something strange happened when the digital versions of the book were made.</p>

<p>The other problem is with source code listings. The source code listings were formatted for print, not for the digital version of the book. I use the line wrapping option in Xcode to dynamically format my source code based on the size of the Workspace window. When I copied the code into the manuscript, I again let line wrapping do its thing. But during the copy editor phase, we were asked to reformat the code listings to 80 columns per line. We did this and the code listings should look good in the print version of the book. However, the 80 column format in the ebook version doesn&#8217;t work. Lines are wrapped at odd places making the source code listings more difficult to read. I believe this would not have been a problem if we left the lines of code as is and let line wrapping do its normal thing.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;m exciting that the book is now available (at least in digital format), but I&#8217;m also not happy about these two formatting issues.</p>

<p>To those of you who have (or will) buy a digital copy of the book, I apologize for the formatting issues with shortcut keys and source code listings. I have made the publisher aware of the issues, and I can only hope that a &#8220;fix&#8221; can be made. (This is my first book, and my first book with this publisher, so I&#8217;m not sure what can and cannot be done with regard to fixing the formatting problems.)</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Tom pointed out to me that the source code format looks better if you reduce the font size in your ebook reader. So give that a try if you are having trouble reading through the source code listings.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> See <a href='/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon'>here</a> for the latest update.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breakpoint on All Exceptions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/breakpoint-on-all-exceptions/"/>
    <published>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/breakpoint-on-all-exceptions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Chapter 9 of the book, I talk about an uncaught exception that will crash the app. Figure 9.4 shows the uncaught exception and the line of code that caused the exception. What I failed to mention is that you might need to set a breakpoint on all exceptions to see the offending line of code. If, for example, Xcode is highlight a line of code in main.m then you need to set a breakpoint on all exceptions.</p>

<p>To set a breakpoint on all exceptions, go to the Breakpoint navigator and click the + button found in the lower left corner. You can set the breakpoint for All, Objective-C, or C++ exceptions. You can also set the break option to On Throw or On Catch. The default settings (All exceptions and On Throw) is all you need to see the offending line of code.</p>

<p><img alt='ExceptionBreakpoint' src='/images/blog/2011-12-10/ExceptionBreakpoint-1.png' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PhotoWheel is Available in the App Store]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/30/photowheel-is-available-in-the-app-store/"/>
    <published>2011-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/30/photowheel-is-available-in-the-app-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PhotoWheel is now available for <a href='http://bit.ly/photowheelapp'>download from the App Store</a>, and it has its very own web site. Visit <a href='http://photowheelapp.com/'>photowheelapp.com</a> to learn more about the app from the book Learning iPad Programming.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips for Writing a Universal App]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/29/tips-for-writing-a-universal-app/"/>
    <published>2011-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/29/tips-for-writing-a-universal-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s another video that was recorded earlier this year. In this video I share some <a href='http://www.informit.com/podcasts/episode.aspx?e=ba19d517-6470-438d-a1a4-290f26b8681c'>tips for writing a universal app</a>. Unfortunately the chapter on writing a universal app was dropped from the book. There just wasn&#8217;t enough room after writing nearly 800 pages. So this short video will have to do for now.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessing the Photo Library]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/17/accessing-the-photo-library/"/>
    <published>2011-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/17/accessing-the-photo-library</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is another brief video I did earlier this year for InformIT. This one is on <a href='http://www.informit.com/podcasts/episode.aspx?e=612f8d91-3244-493d-ae47-71c7efdb13d5'>accessing the photo library</a> from within your iOS application.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Author Intro Video]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/14/author-intro-video/"/>
    <published>2011-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/11/14/author-intro-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>InformIT asked me to record a few video podcasts about our book Learning iPad Programming. A lot has changed since the videos were recorded. Tom has come on as a co-author, and the book was updated to focus on iOS 5. But the videos still give a good sense of what you will learn while reading the book.</p>

<p>That said, here is the <a href='http://www.informit.com/podcasts/episode.aspx?e=f8790bd2-d66d-49c6-a8ec-eb0788ca6c89'>first video</a>. I will post another video in a few days.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>