<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: xcode | Learning iPad Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/category/xcode/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-19T11:20:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Xcode Code Snippets]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/19/using-xcode-code-snippets/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/06/19/using-xcode-code-snippets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you tried Xcode code snippets? If not, head over to InformIT.com to read an article I wrote on being more <a href='http://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1914191'>productive using Xcode code snippets</a>.</p>

<p>Speaking of Xcode code snippets, Cocoaholic has released a Mac app called <a href='http://cocoaholic.com/snippet_edit/'>Snippet Edit</a> that makes it possible to edit your code snippets as well as the standard ones without using Xcode. I haven&#8217;t tried the app yet, but it does look interesting.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/using-xcode-4-2-on-snow-leopard/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/03/24/using-xcode-4-2-on-snow-leopard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few people have recently mentioned to me that they are still running Snow Leopard (Mac OS X 10.6). The latest version of Xcode requires Lion (Mac OS X 10.7), however, Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard is still available for download from the Apple web site.</p>

<p>Learning iPad Programming was written based on Xcode 4.2, so everything covered in the book, with one exception, works with Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard. The one exception is the &#8220;Allows External Storage&#8221; flag in Core Data. This flag is discussed in Chapter 13 on Page 308, and the flag requires Lion. Compile errors are generated if you set this flag while running on Snow Leopard. Not to worry. You can still build the app without setting this flag. The app, after all, is a sample app so for the purpose of learning it is okay to not use this flag when using Xcode 4.2 on Snow Leopard.</p>

<p>To download Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard, go to <a href='https://developer.apple.com/downloads/'>https://developer.apple.com/downloads/</a> and sign in with your Apple Developer ID. In the search box, type &#8220;Xcode 4.2&#8221;. The search results will show Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard (see the screenshot below). Use this version of Xcode if you are still running on Snow Leopard.</p>

<p><img src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/Downloads.png' alt='Downloads' /></p>

<p>As an alternative, you can sign into the <a href='https://developer.apple.com/devcenter/ios/'>iOS Dev Center</a> and scroll down to the Downloads area to find the download link to Xcode 4.2 for Snow Leopard.</p>

<p><img src='/images/blog/2012-03-24/iOS-Dev-Center-Apple-Developer.png' alt='iOS Dev Center Apple Developer' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breakpoint on All Exceptions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/breakpoint-on-all-exceptions/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/breakpoint-on-all-exceptions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Chapter 9 of the book, I talk about an uncaught exception that will crash the app. Figure 9.4 shows the uncaught exception and the line of code that caused the exception. What I failed to mention is that you might need to set a breakpoint on all exceptions to see the offending line of code. If, for example, Xcode is highlight a line of code in main.m then you need to set a breakpoint on all exceptions.</p>

<p>To set a breakpoint on all exceptions, go to the Breakpoint navigator and click the + button found in the lower left corner. You can set the breakpoint for All, Objective-C, or C++ exceptions. You can also set the break option to On Throw or On Catch. The default settings (All exceptions and On Throw) is all you need to see the offending line of code.</p>

<p><img src='/images/blog/2011-12-10/ExceptionBreakpoint-1.png' alt='ExceptionBreakpoint' /></p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>