<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books | Learning iPad Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/category/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-19T11:39:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kirby Turner]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition Coming in Spring 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/23/2edition-coming-spring-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2013/01/23/2edition-coming-spring-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition is coming this spring. Tom and I updated the book to cover new features found in iOS 6 including collection views, <code>UIActivityViewController</code>, unwind segues, simpler iCloud syncing setup, and Cocoa Auto Layout. There&#8217;s also a new chapter on turning your iPad app into a universal app. <a href='http://my.safaribooksonline.com/9780133138702'>Rough Cuts</a> are available at Safari Books Online for those looking to get an early preview of the book.</p>

<p>Also, look for an update to <a href='http://www.photowheelapp.com/'>PhotoWheel</a> coming soon in the App Store. PhotoWheel has been updated to take advantage of new features found in iOS 6. And as with the first edition, the entire source code for the App Store version of PhotoWheel is available in the <a href='https://github.com/kirbyt/PhotoWheel'>github repository</a>.</p>

<p>You maybe asking yourself, &#8220;Should I buy the first edition or wait for the second edition?&#8221; If you are writing an iPad app today that must target iOS 5, then the first edition is the book for you. New features in iOS 6 such as collection views and the activity view controller are not available in iOS 5. However, if you plan to support iOS 6 and newer, then I suggest waiting until the second edition is available for purchase. Or if you like, <a href='http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321885716/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0321885716&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=whitepeaksoft-20'>pre-order Learning iPad Programming, 2nd Edition</a> from Amazon now.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Versions Are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2012/01/27/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took the publisher longer than expected, but I&#8217;m happy to finally report Learning iPad Programming is once again available for <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle</a> and iBooks. And the formatting issues have been corrected.</p>

<p>For those who purchased the Kindle or iBooks version back before they were pulled…I purchased the Kindle and iBooks versions when they were first released at the beginning of December. I was able to update my iBooks version the other day by deleting the book from my device and re-downloading it. Updating the Kindle version is more involved. It requires Amazon to send you an email asking if you wish to update. Amazon does this because installing an update will overwrite your highlights and bookmarks for the book being updated. So far, I have not received my email from Amazon informing me of the update and giving me the option to update. I hope it comes soon because I want to see the latest and greatest on my Kindle.</p>

<p>Update: I found that emailing Amazon at <a href='mailto:kindle-feedback@amazon.com'>kindle-feedback@amazon.com</a> and requesting the latest version is the quickest way to get the updated Kindle version pushed out to your device.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Stores versions will be available soon]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Kindle and iBooks versions of the book have been pulled from the stores while the publisher fixes the content format issues. Once the issues have been fixed, the books will once again be available for purchase.</p>

<p>Also, I&#8217;ve been told that those who have already purchased the ebook will have the option to upgrade to the corrected version.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m very sorry for any inconvenience this may have caused.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kindle and iBooks Versions are Available]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/12/10/kindle-and-ibooks-versions-are-available</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href='http://amzn.to/ipadprogbook-kindle'>Kindle</a> and iBooks Store versions of Learning iPad Programming are now available for purchase and download. This is exciting but at the same time a little disappointing for me. Why? I&#8217;m not happy with some of the formatting errors found in the digital version of the book. The two most obvious formatting errors are shortcut keys and source code listings.</p>

<p>Something strange happened with the shortcut keys. Tom and I were asked to use the Command symbol (⌘) instead of typing the word Command. For example, Option-⌘-4 instead of Command-Option-4 (which was my style before writing this book). Two things happened with the Command symbol. First, in cases were it is displayed in the epub version of the book, the symbol floats up high. In the Kindle version, the symbol appears on its own line. But worse than this is when the letter &#8220;c&#8221; is displayed in place of the Command symbol.</p>

<p>Chapter 2 is the worse hit chapter with regard to the &#8220;c&#8221; problem, as I know call it. So instead of seeing Option-⌘-4 you see Option-c-4. These two keystroke sequences are completely different, and trust me, Tom and I did not type in Option-c-4 in the manuscript. We used the Command symbol, but unfortunately something strange happened when the digital versions of the book were made.</p>

<p>The other problem is with source code listings. The source code listings were formatted for print, not for the digital version of the book. I use the line wrapping option in Xcode to dynamically format my source code based on the size of the Workspace window. When I copied the code into the manuscript, I again let line wrapping do its thing. But during the copy editor phase, we were asked to reformat the code listings to 80 columns per line. We did this and the code listings should look good in the print version of the book. However, the 80 column format in the ebook version doesn&#8217;t work. Lines are wrapped at odd places making the source code listings more difficult to read. I believe this would not have been a problem if we left the lines of code as is and let line wrapping do its normal thing.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;m exciting that the book is now available (at least in digital format), but I&#8217;m also not happy about these two formatting issues.</p>

<p>To those of you who have (or will) buy a digital copy of the book, I apologize for the formatting issues with shortcut keys and source code listings. I have made the publisher aware of the issues, and I can only hope that a &#8220;fix&#8221; can be made. (This is my first book, and my first book with this publisher, so I&#8217;m not sure what can and cannot be done with regard to fixing the formatting problems.)</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> Tom pointed out to me that the source code format looks better if you reduce the font size in your ebook reader. So give that a try if you are having trouble reading through the source code listings.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> See <a href='/2011/12/16/kindle-and-ibooks-stores-versions-will-be-available-soon'>here</a> for the latest update.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manuscript is complete!!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/09/manuscript-is-complete/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.learningipadprogramming.com/2011/09/09/manuscript-is-complete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I made a <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kirbyt/status/112092725574242304'>tweet</a> that I&#8217;ve being waiting to do for a verify long time.</p>

<p><a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kirbyt/status/112092725574242304'><img alt='' src='/images/blog/2011-09-09/tweet-manuscriptcomplete.png' /></a></p>

<p>Yep, the manuscript is complete. A part of me thought this day would never come. But it&#8217;s here and I couldn&#8217;t be happier. Tom and I will be doing some edits over the next few weeks then the book heads off to the printers.</p>

<p>With the writing part finally out of the way, I can turn my attention to this web site. I have a number of how to blog posts queued up that will expand on the book. Stay tune. The best is yet to come.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>